James Bergen

16340 Hanna Rd. | Lutz, FL 33549 | Phone: 631-921-2286 | jmbergen922@gmail.com

Professional Summary

I am an experienced SQA Test Engineer with a bachelor's degree in Management Information Systems. I am experienced with programming languages such as C# and Ruby. I am a team player who enjoys writing code and solving problems. As a software engineer, I am confident that my background in quality assurance and test automation will bring value to any development team.

Technical Skills

Programming/Web: C#, Ruby, JavaScript, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS

Database/DBMS: SQL, MS SQL Server 2012

Tools: Selenium WebDriver, NUnit, WATIR, Cucumber, Visual Studio

2012, TFS

Experience

Bisk

Software Quality Assurance Test Engineer

February 2016 - Present

- Built and maintained an automation framework using C#, Selenium WebDriver and NUnit
- Created regression tests for the Learning Management System and university marketing sites
- Conducted peer code reviews
- Assisted with manual testing and reported any defects for development team to address
- Within a year I was promoted from Associate SQA Test Engineer to SQA Test Engineer

West Point Underwriters Software Development Engineer in Test January 2013 – February 2016

- Created automation scripts for regression testing utilizing Ruby, WATIR and Cucumber
- Designed and implemented new tools for QA Automation such as a rating utility, force renewals tool, and environment dashboard
- Trained new hires on QA Automation process and tools
- Led IT department lunch and learns to review QA Automation process
- Implemented bug fixes and re-factored code for existing QA tools
- Provided technical support for QA team

West Point Underwriters Quality Assurance Analyst April 2012 – January 2013

- Interpreted requirements and applied business logic to create test cases
- Identified defects and provided detailed documentation with steps to recreate
- Worked with SDET to maintain automation scripts utilizing Ruby, WATIR and Cucumber

Education

University of South Florida, Tampa, FL Bachelor of Science in Management Information Systems May 2011